# Srikanth (Srik) Gorthy

(773) 807 9898 | Srik.Gorthy@u.northwestern.edu | 1309 Maple Ave 2W Evanston IL 60201 linkedin.com/in/srikgorthy | github.com/srikg-msai22

## **SUMMARY**

Multifaceted professional with 8.5+ years experience in technological spaces such as Data Sciences, Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence. Additionally, I have 5.5+ years experience in leadership roles such as entrepreneur, solutions architect and team builder. Motivated to build innovations and looking for exciting opportunities to cultivate and deliver value.

## **EDUCATION**

Northwestern University, IL, USA

[Graduating Dec 2022\*]

Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence [Current GPA: 4.0]

Indian Institute of Management, Bangalore, India

[Jul 2017 - Jun 2018]

Part-time Certificate, Business Analytics and Intelligence

BITS-Pilani, India [Jan 2009 - Dec 2012]

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours), Chemical

## **EXPERTISE**

Skills Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Speech Processing, Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Data Science, Algorithms and Optimization, Predictive Modeling, Correspondence Analysis, Recommender Systems, Human Computer Interaction, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Computer Vision, Semantic Web

Tools Machine Learning: Python, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Scikit Learn, Keras, AWS Sagemaker Data Science: R, RStudio, NLTK, SQL, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, D3.js, Databases: SQL [MySQL, SQL Server, PostgreSQL], AWS [Redshift, RDS]
Web Development: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Django, RShiny, Plumber Other: AWS [EC2, S3, ECS], Google Colab, KNIME, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Git, Docker

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- Co-Authored a paper titled "Automated Intelligent Test Planning using Deep Learning Techniques" for the Global AMD Technical Authors Conference in November '21
- Co-Authored a paper titled "Machine Learning-Based Failure Analysis for Verification and Validation" in the Global AMD Technical Authors Conference in November '20

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Advanced Micro Devices(AMD), Hyderabad

[Jan 2020 - Sep 2021]

MTS, ML/AI Software Engineer

Drove innovation in driver integration validation team as Senior Leader building ML/AI models and automating existing manual workflows

- Developed an MLP Neural Network model to yield test plans for given driver code changes automating and standardizing existing complex processes saving 1+ hours/day
- Produced multiple Neural Network models tailored to specific areas to identify root cause of a given driver failure saving 5+ FTE resources in a quarter
- Created an ensemble of 1-hidden layered model and Naïve Bayes model to identify bug severity diminishing manual evaluations by 30% in a quarter
- Took initiative and mentored ten teammates in Machine Learning(ML) and ML Mythbusting

TVAlly, Hyderabad

[Jul 2017 - Dec 2019]

## CEO and Co-founder

Conceptualized and founded an online music streaming platform for independent music in India with 2000+ users

- Developed a content-based recommender system from scratch; scraped 10000+ songs/tracks; automated track elements annotations; crafted 100+ playlists, decreased search time by 75% and increasing activity rate by 50%
- Produced multiple dashboards for executive meetings showcasing various KPIs reducing time spent on generating ad hoc reports by 90%
- Instructed, and led data science team of four helping generate models estimating ideal web page journeys, estimating customer life lengths and aiding marketing efforts

# Google, Hyderabad

[Aug 2015 - Jul 2017]

## Analyst - Trust and Safety, Google Search

Led efforts to reduce spam and abuse in the Trust and Safety team building scalable solutions

- Identified opportunity and created an in-house ML team from scratch to yield scalable solutions; Managed and delivered 5 projects in 2 quarters
- Produced an ensemble model leveraging Linear Discriminant Analysis and Gradient
   Boosting Machines to identify gibberish on HTML page decreasing spam by 35% in a quarter
- Employed NLP techniques alongside GMMs to segregate unstructured user feedback into action items cutting down time-to-action by 20% and improving response rate by 50%
- Trained 150+ employees across locations on ML techniques to increase ML adoption

## LatentView Analytics, Chennai

[Dec 2012 - Jul 2015]

Senior Analyst

[Oct 2014 - Jul 2015]

Created solutions for client projects in roles assuming responsibility

- Identified causal factors to enhance an album's ranking on the Billboard Charts utilizing PCA for a multinational music conglomerate leading a team of 2
- Crafted strategy to convert prepaid to postpaid accounts using clustering techniques for an Indonesian telephone services provider working onsite improving monthly conversions from 3.5% to 15% in 2 quarters

<u>Analyst</u> [Dec 2012 - Sep 2014]

Worked on building predictive model solutions for various domains

- Trained 2500 models for various segments of 2 billion rows dataset with 2500 dimensions to detect credit card frauds for a global credit card company aiding fraud prevention by 40%
- Modeled a credit scoring system for a Middle Eastern County's Credit Bureau with an AUC of 0.75. Presented it onsite to clients and provided UAT
- Prepared brand perceptual charts by scraping Twitter data through Correspondence Analysis for a multinational beverage brand to identify potential market gaps
- Prepared material and onboarded 200+ new employees on ML

## **TALKS AND SESSIONS**

- "Natural Language Processing" at Geekle's Python for ML and Al Summit 2021 in April '21
- "A perspective on Artificial Intelligence" at University of Madras, Chennai, Hyderabad, India in January '21
- "Natural Language Processing" at Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, Hyderabad, India in November '20

## **AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS**

- Was awarded "Spot bonus" and 7 "Peer Bonus" awards for excellence of delivery and collaborative work at Google between 2015 and 2017
- Was awarded "Encore Award" for diligence and on-time delivery at LatentView in 2014